14 Peaks: Nothing Is Impossible is a documentary film directed by Torquil Jones.
In 2019, Nepalese mountain climber Nirmal “Nims” Purja set out to do the unthinkable by
climbing the world’s fourteen highest summits in less than seven months.
(The previous record was eight years).
He called the effort “Project Possible 14/7” and saw it as a way to
inspire others to strive for greater heights in any pursuit.
The film follows his team as they seek to defy naysayers
and push the limits of human endurance.
Himself, played by Nirmal Purja.
Himself, played by Jimmy Chin.
Himself, played by Reinhold Messner.
Herself, played by Klára Kolouchová.
Himself (archive footage), played by Conrad Anker.
14 Peaks: Nothing Is Impossible is a 2021 documentary film directed by Torquil Jones, and produced by Noah Media Group, Little
Monster Films and Torquil Jones with Nirmal Purja, Jimmy Chin and Elizabeth Vasarhelyi as executive producers.
The film follows Nepalese mountaineer Nirmal Purja and his team as they attempt to climb all
14 eight-thousander peaks within a then record time of under seven months.
The previous record was over seven years.
A significant portion of the footage was taken by the expedition team, while additional images and interviews were added later by the director, including interviews with Reinhold Messner
(who called the feat "a unique statement in the history of mountaineering"), and other major high-altitude mountaineers, and Purja's family (including his wife and brothers).
The film premiered at the DOC NYC Film Festival, and was
released on Netflix on 29 November 2021.
The film explores themes of mountain, mountaineer,
k2, mountain climbing, mountaineering.